intentionally making a product selection
for your personal use surrounding
whether something has a bug Bounty
program or not not only pays dividends
from a security perspective um but also
can pay actual dividends Lally for for
for you to get bounties that's that's
great
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah man I wish my my jumper my jumper
was here my sweater sweater it's not why
do you say it with an American accent
can you say sweater did you not say
sweater at all sweater sweater that
that's it got it got it up man every all
right man all right cool well um today
everybody we have critical thinking's
own
Brandon right here our writer for the
hacker notes and uh I'm excited for this
episode because I've wanted to have
Brandon on for a while because I think
his story is really good um and it's
amazing to me to see how much progress
has been made in 10 months as of today
actually uh of of working working
together and um yeah having a mentorship
type thing but to be honest most of the
time it's just me being like yeah that's
that's right continue doing that like
that yeah that's sounds great to me um
so Brandon I I'll give you an
opportunity here to to give us a little
bit of of uh self history and then also
as I'm reading over this document I'm
realizing that I think we have a little
bit of a different story on how we we
met uh originally so I'm interested to
hear your take and then and then tell
mine sure so in terms of background
experience um I started in cyber when I
was 16 so 10 years now which has been
a very wild and long um career so far if
I start going gracing that's probably
why if I'm being honest but it's been
good I started off very much in the blue
team and system administration stuff
always with the goal of wanting to be a
pentester and wanted to go into pentes
him
so throughout that progress and
throughout that career I grinded out SS
because that's what I believe was the
only way to get there but more on that
later um and I've been testing for the
past 6 years now and started bug hunting
10 months ago so it's been a it's been
an interesting journey and lots to talk
about but you can't fit 10 years into 10
minutes really no you can't man and
actually I was kind of surprised to hear
that it was it was you know 10 years
that you've been you've been at it now
and I was like oh man he's been he's
been at this for quite a while and then
I'm realizing yeah I've also been I've
been doing this for for 16 years I I
started like hacking stuff when I was
like 12 dude um and and so it's crazy
how um how much how much time it takes
but it it makes a lot of it it makes
sense to me that it that you
progressed um so much faster than a lot
of the other people in the bug Bounty
industry that I've seen uh given how how
focused you've been on pentesting and I
think also you were a pentester even
before we started you know training and
stuff together but um yeah no that makes
a that makes a lot more sense um and
then okay so so it says here in the
notes that that did you suggest that you
be a writer for critical thinking or did
I suggest that uh so I suggested it
really okay I'll give you my I'll give
you my context and where how I thought
this started okay so the hacker notes
originally from my context started off
in my iPhone and I have a lot of like
nonsensical scribbles voice notes memos
all of it um which basically highlighted
the key takeaways from each episode
which I found useful and which I thought
other hackers would find useful as well
and it got to a point where I was like
I'm doing this for myself but other
people might like benefit from this yeah
and then this is sort of tied into the
whole me messaging you and reaching out
and going hey um I'm doing this thing
called The Hacker notes um I'm looking
for mentorship if I done this for the
Pod would you provide mentorship see how
it goes and I was expecting to be
ignored I'm not going to lie I was not
expecting a response at all and you
responded a couple of days later and
this was over Christmas I think when I
reached out yeah yeah and um I was like
wow okay and then we me you and Joe
jumped on the call and then uh off it
went really we gave the hack and I was a
guy and it went quite well yeah yeah
dude okay so that it must have just been
perfect timing because I I remember also
getting some advice from a respected
podcaster you know saying hey you you
have to get somebody to to write notes
for your for your podcast like there has
to be a text version because um you know
you're doing the video thing you're
doing the audio thing it just makes
sense to also have text right and
because some people you know there's
various different ways for people to
consume media um so I was thinking about
it I think at the time and our our
writer you know had had moved along and
and I was like I really got to find
someone else so I think you just kind of
like hit the nail on the head uh when
when you asked I was like yeah that's
exactly what we need I I I accept you
know um it's funny cuz the actual
message that sat in my notes for a while
because I like how do I position this so
I'm not like some Creep from the
internet but also sounds good enough
that you would respond back so sat on my
notes for like a good couple of days of
like various iterations and then I got
to the point where I thought no I'm just
going to send it and see how it goes
well well clearly it worked man clearly
it worked and since there has been one
other individual who has has success y
pulled off this um I'll provide services
for mentorship sort of thing um I'm just
going to go ahead and put it out there I
am not open to that Arrangement right
now I'm so sorry like I I just can't do
Bron's too much of a handful I can't I
can't take on any more mes so um but
yeah I I think it's been really fun too
and we you know in our meetings we've
kind of been talking recently the the
way we have it structured for for for
the listeners is um is you know once a
week we'll meet up and we'll kind of do
a sync for like
you know 30 minutes to an hour on what's
what's going on in the bug Bounty stuff
for this past you know week or whatever
what kind of strategies we're using you
know if you've got any technical
questions that sort of thing um and yeah
I mean it's it's gone incredibly well
and it's been really exciting to see how
you've grown and uh also you know just
kind of debrief along the way because a
lot of this has just been a like a
straight upward trajectory there hasn't
been a lot of you know Hills and hills
and and stuff so um yeah what do you
what do you think about that whole
experience
um what are what are some some takeaways
or some thoughts you've had from that
mentorship process that just G give give
give a brother a grade here like how
what kind of stuff was helpful and what
kind of stuff wasn't helpful well what's
funny now looking back with the context
I have on you now which I didn't have
before when I used to report stuff and
either or get downgraded by triage or
not underst or anything like that I'll
just be raging in our Discord like
what's going on it's being that great
like what BL blah and just being so like
fiery and angry and you guiding me
through the emotional side of bug Bounty
was very valuable because my default was
to just get really annoyed for not much
reason actually Y and now I realize how
busy you are and how structured
everything is you must have just been
looking at your disc thinking oh no why
have I taken him on no no dude i' I've
been there man I've been there and it's
it's really frustrating you know I I
think there aren't really a lot of
industries that I can think of that are
results you know money for results right
like like um like book Bounty is so if
you are delivering something that you
perceive to be a high quality result and
expecting to get paid for it you know
and and then it it doesn't happen that's
extremely demoralizing and infuriating
right especially when you have put so
much time and effort into our poc's into
our our reports like we do right so I
think I think that that that's an
interesting thing that you pointed out
as as one of the top uh you know pieces
of of information you pulled away from
our mentorship is is that whole like
emotional regulation and um you know I I
guess there's also that aspect of
knowing what kind of things you can say
back to triers and and that it's not
like nail in the coffin I just lost my
bounty it's let's have a conversation
right yeah that's it yeah that and it's
funny because even though I've been on
the other side of the fence with bug
bounty in the triage of position
managing quite small
programs until you've actually reported
stuff as a hunter you can't recreate
that emotional like roller coaster or
that context or anything like that you
have to really go out do it experience
it fail go again um but yeah the
mentorship that was probably the most
valuable thing for me because I think if
this whole thing didn't happen and we
weren't here talking right now I
probably would have gotten so annoyed at
the time and I would have just went nope
not for me yeah well I think and I think
there was um just from like a technical
perspective I think there we've worked
through it a couple like quality
vulnerability things and stuff like that
but but to be honest a lot of because I
think you've been focused on being a
pentester for so long I think you had a
really good base of like Tech tech
knowledge and ability to approach these
targets so a lot of it was more like
yeah you're on the right track stick at
it keep at it keep at it spend more time
on this target dive deeper here this
isn't a real lead this is a real lead
you know that sort of thing um so I
think it it's a lot easier just from a
mentor perspective with you to to point
people in the right direction because or
to point you in the right direction
because you know you already had a sense
for what an attack Vector looks like and
that sort of thing yeah yeah I think the
other side of it putting the mental and
like softer skills away the technical
piece was quite valuable because the
client side stuff that is very much your
jam like everyone knows everyone who
listens knows that and that isn't an
area for me where I ever deep dived in
and spent the time to craft and learn
because I think there's a lot of
intricacies and it's very much an alive
and living ecosystem which changes a lot
as browsers change and so on um and I
just sort of abandoned that and I think
we'll touch upon this later I think but
traditional pen testing and bearing in
mind I started 10 years ago and all the
advice I got was very like Network
Harden traditional pent test experience
um it goes against that style of bug
hunting I think in my opinion because
there's a lot of focused around
traditional attack vectors more from a
network perspective and I'm speaking
from experience when I tried to break in
but equally with web app more around the
traditional like web app hardcore stuff
rather than more client side Focus yeah
and I think Jason I think it might have
been Jason hadik touched upon this
before and I think it's because a lot of
the material I mean it's getting better
now but a lot of the material
traditionally that was built around this
was around that traditional like web app
hacking stuff and not much focus on
JavaScript analysis or anything like
that sure so I think that's been really
for me incredibly valuable to
like bance my attributes in all areas of
hacking if you see what I mean yeah yeah
and it's it's it's all too easy to go
one One Direction or the other right and
I think to become a balanced hacker you
really have to often intentionally
balance rebalance yourself right um and
I I often find myself moving too much in
the client side Direction and being like
you know yeah and and because at the end
of the day I mean unless your
application has a specifically um
intense uh threat model uh most the time
what you're going to achieve with client
side stuff is is a high right you know
at Max um and while a high feels great
and keeps the keep the pockets loaded uh
you know it isn't as fun as popping like
a critical where you're just you know
dumping everyone's pii and it's like you
know you got access to everything right
um so I know for me you know just and
it's funny because uh these mentorship
sessions have also turned into like I
don't know like group therapy like Bug
Hunter group therapy where I'm like hey
Brandon guess what I guess what learned
about myself this past week you know and
like and like and so it's good to sit
down and like talk about stuff right
because um I I also get to regurgitate
these these lessons that I'm like
realizing for myself as well but it it's
it's far too easy to leverage in One
Direction or the other right um and so I
think one of the things that I want to
try to work on in Q4 this year and go
going into 2025 is is like swinging back
onto that server side realm and using
the client side stuff to inform the way
that I attack the the server side more
directly um rather than getting caught
up in the weeds of like oh that looks
like a weird sanitization or that looks
like a weird little you know code flow
that they've got there um so yeah I
would say we've done a few hacker alongs
as well for people that aren't aware and
it has been interesting because you like
when I blink you've got like Dev tools
open like straight away like and you
start going down that of getting
familiar with an app which I never used
to really follow or have much knowledge
on and that for me was really
interesting to see because if you're not
uh predominantly doing much client side
hacking or have much client side bugs
that isn't intuitive at first but then
as you start to use like the dev Dev
tools and doing some like Dynamic
analysis to inform your hunt and inform
your testing going forward that's where
it starts to get quite interesting but
that's one thing that definely stood out
to me when we done our first hack along
was I blinked and like Dev to you're
like break
break I love it it it is great and it
really does inform a lot um yeah when I
think that's a takeaway and we'll we'll
go to takeaways from this past life hack
man as well because uh Brandon dude
Brandon I have to say man you had me
sweating there for a little bit at this
last Live Hack man because um you know I
was like okay you know this is cool my
mentee you know is going to a live
hacking event like this is fun and then
like you messaged me like one hour into
the event you're like dude I just popped
a crit and I'm like oh [__] is this how
we're going to start like am I GNA I
gotta hustle so I I um you know for a
little while I was sweating there about
whether my mentee was gonna outperform
me and if the if I was GNA need to write
something for you to become become the
mentee now um but uh it it turned out
quite great so we'll we'll we'll come
back to some of the L um takeaways but
definitely this time around one of the
one of the big on for me that that's
relevant to this was yeah that whole
aspect of um and I think this might be
like a nice Axiom like something that
that we should have like one one of the
takeaways from previous pods that I've
always held with me is is Jason hax's
quote on on recon the purpose of Recon
is to find more apps to hack right and I
think um one of the axioms that I would
like to you know sort of propose out
there is that the client side can really
really be useful in in determining in in
informing the way that you you make
assumptions about the server side um and
I missed that this event man and it
hurts me because um another hacker you
know just found some really crazy stuff
with that and after I sat down and
reviewed some of the um the the material
uh some of the vules with them um
something really really clear to me
stuck out and I was like oh what have I
done man that feedback that is and we
keep we keep saying that we'll go back
to it but we keep talking about it let's
just do it let's just do it I don't know
yeah let's do it okay continue go ahead
but that feedback that you get in that
LH context are you're able to see what
other people are hacking and get that
immediate oh I missed that or oh okay I
maybe didn't spot that is just so like
you don't you don't get that really
anywhere else in bug Bounty unless you
collab and even if you do collab you
don't get it to that extent because
people have literally spent three weeks
on the same sort of areas as you have in
the same we context and then you can
talk about it and see what they found
and that for me it just felt like
another piece of the puzzle falling into
place and I was like this is great why
wasn't I here before yeah it it's such
it's such high feedback right like like
you think about the way we we are
traditionally educated right you know
you you go you study you you take an
exam imagine if you just never got a
grade you never got they no one ever
told you if you had the answers right or
if you had the answers wrong right and
and um
and so I think you know live hacking
events sort of is the closest we can get
as hackers to getting a grade on our
work because if you if you look at all
the other hackers around you that are
extremely talented and you look at their
work and you say okay well probably
between the combination of the 50 of us
you know uh somebody you know somebody
found pretty much everything there is to
find but then then you do it again the
next time and then there's still more
things to find um which is just the sort
of mindboggling
um thing that happens with these live
hacking events so man just Fran Frozen
by the way like every time every time it
just it doesn't
seem it just doesn't whatever he's
stacking in his head fundamentally do
not stack in mine yeah I don't how does
he extrapolate the he done some really
cool stuff at this LH and shil but
that's what we can say and it was great
yeah dude it it's it's always amazing
man I'm so glad you got to go and
experience it because it is really um it
is really amazing and I think for me I
to see you go through it and to see you
be amazed by it it renews it a little
bit for me because it's become a little
bit of um like a a normal thing for me
and then now when I hear you talking
about it like oh my gosh you know it it
really is amazing so it does it does
make me um make me realize that yeah if
you if anybody has the opportunity to go
to a live hacking event I I would really
take it regardless of of the uh of the
cost or whether it's it's you know how
much it work it takes or or if you have
to pay your own flight or pay your own
hotel or whatever because the the
opportunity to be around other hackers
and see how they think about the same
application it's pretty rare because in
a pentest contest as well like
oftentimes most you get is a a pentest
report from another company or like
maybe you get paired if you're lucky you
get paired with one other pentester to
like pair work on a project right so
it's it's so crazy to see more than two
hackers hacking on one thing well this
is it and like the time constraints as
well I haven't ever looked at so for the
past 10 months my bug bounty hunting has
been incredibly broken up like maybe two
hours a day here there whenever I can
fit it in around my schedule um and I
managed to negotiate some time off work
to focus on this LH this time around so
I got
somewhat unexpected invite through and I
was like I have to try and make this
work because you don't get this every
day um and being able to spend that much
time on the Target and also have that
feedback from other hackers I feel like
it levels you up so much more and quite
quickly in some ways because of that
immediate feedback and being able to
have TW three weeks worth of context on
the target yeah yeah yeah so so what do
you think about let me ask you this for
the people that haven't experienced what
it's like to be a full-time hacker what
was that transition like the the the two
to three hours like were you
experiencing a lot of or two to three
hours too a full day right or maybe you
know a 12 hour day or whatever right so
were you experiencing a lot of mental
fatigue how is your focus you know where
where where was the burnout that's a
leading question because I know where
that's going but but uh yeah it hit me
with that it was interesting
because where it was for such a long
period that it was it was like a roller
coaster in a way um and I think it
started off very like energized really
great like yeah let's bang bang bang
getting all these things but then there
are points and they when you're trying
to hack something where you get stuck
and usually when I get stuck I would
have like a day or two in between of
doing other stuff then coming back to it
and being refreshed going ah how didn't
I see that before yeah this time however
when you're going at it and you're
looking at one
target having to like coach yourself
through that mentally because it's very
easy to fall into a hole and be like Oh
I'm so bad I should be able to get this
why aren't I getting this and you can
sort of fall into this like pit of just
despair and you really need to try and
avoid that or just get yourself out of
it so that was very interesting for me
because I hadn't ever really had that at
all spending that long on one target
dude it's crazy how much of this podcast
which we we really do try to orient
towards actionable bug Bounty tips that
we actually spend talking about mental
because I think bug Bounty is a
particularly task tasking mental thing
right like you tasking ta taxing that's
what I'm trying to say I'm like I'm like
what what am I trying to say here um
it's very taxing right like it it takes
a lot of energy it t there's a lot of
little like pits around there that you
can fall into and and make a mistake um
and and it's at every turn too it's not
just when you're when you're a beginner
right it's as you're even you know as
you're getting more advanced are you
burning yourself out if you're at the
live hacking events how do you deal with
the competition aspect um yeah it it's
it is it is really it is really odd uh
but yeah so so I mean there's definitely
that mental aspect of it right um how
was the how were the the energy levels
and and how hard did you put yourself
for this
L yeah so I
originally basically tried to burn all
fuel in the tank and just go for it and
I put like every aspect or tried to put
every human aspect of my life on hold
and then I would like forget to go to
the gym because I was like halfway
through like a chain of doing something
incredible but that long term really did
work against me because just because
you're in an LH you still need to like
do stuff and like refresh yourself and I
messaged you and I was like how's
everything going and you were like well
I'm sort of being less productive now so
I'm going to take like half a day off
and for me I was trying to Brute Force
through that period And I was like no we
we we're going to keep finding more bugs
we got to keep pushing and then when I
spoke to you I realized that it probably
wasn't the right approach because with
hindsight looking back that really
didn't work with me it worked against me
and I should have just taken the break
time to refresh and go for it and I feel
like I was
spending between
minimum seven between 7 to 12 hours a
day some days um on the target trying to
really peel it back and understand the
context um which was great but again you
need breaks man like just because you're
in an LH you don't turn into Superman or
I mean some people do but I certainly
yeah I feel that man yeah and I think
you know in retrospect when we had our
conversation um about the intensity and
and what my my advice was you know for
you going into the live hacking event a
lot of what we spent our time on was
like you know make sure you're trying to
get other other aspects of your life
unlock right like you know get get all
your tasks around the house done get get
your house clean you know take your
girlfriend out for a couple dates you
know that sort of thing communicate with
loved ones uh you know try to try to
reduce your task load as much as you can
for the live hacking event and then sort
of lock in and focus but then there's
also this this aspect of like as you're
as you're pushing as you're going hard
um you know you have to do that
self-care piece and and it's it's also
really inspiring for me to hear you say
like oh I forgot about all these human
aspects like I think this is a quote
from you from from our chats I forgot
about all these human aspects like
eating and going to the gym and I I
often forget about eating but I often
don't think about going to the gym as
like a human aspect but it really is and
and and it's funny you know you use that
that's specific piece because I think
the gym is one of those first things
that that goes for me and like if I if I
don't do it first thing in the morning
right it's not getting done that day for
sure like if I even sit down at my
computer I'm gonna blink and it's going
to be five o'clock and I'm you're six
o'clock 7 o'clock I'm gonna be exhausted
and then I'm I'm not g to do it you know
I feel like it's one of them things as
well like once you get it done you get
so much of an Roi on it just get it done
because you feel good it sets a time for
the rest of the day you can smash this
target whatever you're looking at and it
just works whereas when you're or where
I found myself in the LH I was very much
in the mindset of oh if I'm not hacking
there's someone else globally that is
which might mean we do and it just fell
into this like horrible like tsunami of
cascading thoughts of if I'm not hacking
someone else's and once I got myself out
of it and just focused on hacking like
doing good hacking but also doing other
things as well I felt a lot more
comfortable and just had a lot more fun
as well yeah yeah absolutely wow okay so
there's there's uh it's a lot man what
what did you what did you think about my
what did you think about the results of
my advice for you to stick to a specific
portion of the application for the whole
duration of the event because I know
that there are some people that that
jump around and try to attack every
little piece of scope I don't know how
fron consistently finds crits on both
targets uh in multi-target events I I
just don't get it um but what is your
what is your thought on on that that
methodology yeah so for me it most
definitely works and I feel like with LH
and Targets in general there was
somewhat of
a meta approach depending on the Target
and for this one instead of focusing on
an individual application I'm more
focused on ecosystem that the
application resided in because there's a
lot of interconnected components and
different apis different applications
which had like their own um
authorization their own permissions but
yet they depended on each other and
depended on these permissions which were
set in other applications and for me I
focused a lot
on the ecosystem of my specific uh area
which I focus on which done really
really well because on a Target like
this you can lock a lot and I feel like
that lended itself really well to a
Target like this um but that approach
definitely worked because I was able to
peel back the layers and get into places
where people would either not think to
go to or they would have gotten bored
and not have even bothered trying to go
that deep so there's a lot of attack
surface which felt relatively unseen
which was quite nice in my context yeah
I think with some of these bigger
programs too
um obviously there's there's a lot of
hackers on the bigger programs and in
bigger scope on the bigger programs
right but um if you can weasle your way
into you know just one or two layers
deeper than the normal hacker goes
there's really a lot of a lot of results
to be found there um so spending some
time unlocking scope I think is really
important and and I think the I like
your term ecosystem hacking where where
you're not necessarily focusing on on
one on one you know app but a ecosystem
of apps that sort of integrate together
um and trying to get it in such a
configured state where those apps um
unlock different different pieces of
each other and give you access to deeper
deeper deeper scope I think that's I
think that's probably pretty widely
applicable but it's definitely pretty
applicable for Amazon
because the target is public so we can
be we can be public about that but um
yeah yeah I think that's definitely the
case yeah the the ecosystem approach did
work well and when I feel like when you
start looking at a Target you get a feel
for the different Integrations and if
they offer documentation read the
documentation and I just feel like when
there's so many different apps and apis
that depend so heavily on each other but
Implement completely different access
controls built on completely different
Technologies there's going to be a lot
of different contexts which reside in
each with and discrepancies across them
and I massively tried to profit off that
and it worked yeah yeah so I want to
take a a turn here and um and go back to
your LG experience I just just spending
time with you in in Vegas um when you
weren't competing at the live hacking
events I saw um how powerful of a
networker you you are and uh this the
one of the reasons you got invited this
Live Hack event I I imagine was you were
plus one not only by me but by several
other hackers that you've met um uh you
know in Vegas and and talk to about the
bug ecosystem um and so I mean I don't I
don't even know how to phrase this
question I mean do you have advice
relating to that or is it just uh like
something that that you do instinctually
that um has paid off really well for you
across these these couple
interactions yeah that's interesting I
think for me it feels very natural and
instinctual it doesn't I don't it
doesn't require effort as such I
genuinely enjoy speaking to people and
like a lot of the connections I made in
Vegas which I attended as a guest not as
a hacker um I made some really good
friends and like Greg Sunday hamek um
loads and loads of people I just would
literally go up to someone and be like
hey what bugs did you find or can you
show me some bug stuff like that that's
exactly what I was going to say man I
was going to say like do you ask the
technical questions because I think
people despite what you would think 99%
of the people in this industry are love
to talk about their bugs right that's
like a flattering question right and so
have people responded well to that very
well very well and I think when the LH
environment what I find very interesting
about it is that it's quite competitive
in the sense that there's a leaderboard
and then when someone gets a p there's a
ding and everyone just like turns around
like they're programmed I was definitely
programmed by the end of the L yeah um
but the sense of community and like
collaboration and helping people out
that is like a very very good piece of
the whole scene that you don't really
get much of anywhere else when you're
hunting or when you're hunting I don't
think and just going up to people and
asking about their bugs or like what
they're hacking
on I literally didn't get a single
person be like no stop talking to me who
are you everyone was very welcome in
very very nice and for me that's what
made my Vagas experience I think or one
of the things that made the Vagas
experience and I feel like that's what
made me want to get onto the LH scene so
much more than I already did because it
just felt so welcoming and so it just it
was good it's crazy man I think over the
course of my entire bug Bounty career
I've been doing this since 2017 right so
so seven years um I think I've only had
somebody say like no I don't want to
talk about my bugs like like maybe three
times over that whole that whole course
of time um and so it's definitely it's
definitely very rare and it's also
something that that made me um you know
feel very comfortable starting this
podcast because I was like you know what
people love to talk about this you know
they love to talk about their bugs
because it's something we're all
passionate about in general right um and
I definitely have had people say like
okay well it's different that uh you
know going on a podcast where thousands
and thousands of people listen every
week and and you know talk about my bugs
rather than you know just hey Justin
yeah check this out you know because
it's it's a difference in distribution
right but um I think in general I think
I think that's absolutely the case um
all right let let me let me look here
back at better at our dock real quick um
yeah I think we're good on the live
hacking event stuff did you have
anything else you wanted to add to that
whole that whole
flow
no how was organiz Organization for you
or I don't know what is wrong with me
today or organizing how is how was
organizing all of the um all of the data
that you got because you spent a very
long time on on one target for this
event right this is actually kind of a
long event um so yeah what what was that
like and did you use your notes slash
you know different burp files or
whatever yeah absolutely so for people
that don't know me but Justin knows this
very well if I'm not taking notes and I
mean really good notes I am as close to
useless as one can get I need to I just
have to take notes otherwise it doesn't
get done or it gets forgotten about and
for me throughout the whole LH I made a
lot of notes and a lot of contextual
based notes and even voice notes as well
so I could just jump back into it when I
was going the next day or if there was
something that I really needed to stick
that I didn't want to forget and for the
entire time I was hacking remote
fantastic notes were going well I was
using them I was ticking things off
attack vectors bang bang bang in
person I was just the the mental energy
it took me to like focus and just get on
and try and do that I don't know why it
just wasn't working I think it might be
like quite ADHD because there's so much
stuff going on so many hackers and like
collabs and like other people's bugs
that just went straight out the window
that's a great Point man it is it is
actually a very different skill set to
hack with with people in person um than
at at home right I think it's very
distracting it's very hard to actually
sit down at the live hacking event
itself and hack um because there is such
social there's there's that social
presence where You' be like oh I I so
rarely get to see XYZ you know I want to
go talk to them um but also so many
distractions around um and I think
that's why a lot of times there's
there's that extra aspect of they they
put in this this uh bonus of best bug on
the event day right because they want
hackers to continue trying to
collaborate and hack together ra rather
than just kind of you know screwing
around while they're there you know on
on event but um I think they're there
the inverse is also true there are some
hackers some hackers oxb that um goes to
the live hacking event and just somehow
enters Cosmic mode and and just like
like when they're around their their
people they just become this like
hacking God and always find a critical
at the event on the event day somehow or
like at the night before in the hotel at
3:00 am. or something like that um so
it's weird how different hackers respond
differently to that pressure yeah man
that's I that I don't think that's ever
going to be me I hate to call it out now
but I don't think that's me I'm very
much notes tick it off attack vectors
very much I need silence just to
properly get into things and to get into
my like workflow um but with that being
said when you're with other hackers at
the LG it brings an entirely different
set of opportunities to collab on which
are equally as powerful because you have
many different skill sets people with
their own niches lots of different
contexts as well and understandings and
that can come together and do some
really really cool collabs and really
cool bugs yeah yeah I agree with that
man there's there's definitely there's
definitely both sides of that I think it
I think it does take practice as well I
know I know ngi is another guy that
often finds something you know at the
event and day of the event and I would
not really think that that he would be
one of those guys you know ngly I know
you're listening but he often you know
goes to these events is like you know
let's party man you know like but but
then also he somehow rolls up to the
hotel and opens up his laptop is like
look at this SF that's like one little
tidbit away from being exploitable and
somebody's like just just just do this
and then it's like crit crit you know
like so it's great it's great so that
that collaboration piece definitely I
don't know that it fully counteracts the
ability to sit down and like focus and
and get deep and and have your notes but
um it definitely is a a stroke in the
other
direction for sure and I think it
definitely depends on what type of
hacker you are and what personality as
well I think that's another big thing as
well in bug Bounty and LH you get to see
how people's personalities and how they
interact and how they hack really has a
massive play because as you said some
people can just lock in and find some
intense things where me for example I
was just it was more effort trying to
put my laptop password in in in itself
than just trying to open up B and hack
something on the day so yeah it's
interesting to see really interesting
I'll throw this out there for The
Listener base as well and it's something
that I think I've mentioned to you in
the past but one of the things I've I've
learned over years of going to the live
hacking events is in order to be a good
collaborator you really have to take
your your co-collaborator you know the
person you're collaborating with their
attack factors or their ideas or their
things that they think are sketchy
really seriously more seriously than you
would probably think you should um
because for me you know somebody will
come up to me and be like hey Justin
this is sketchy and I'm like I'll look
at it and I'll be like you know for
whatever reason this just doesn't hit me
as sketchy or or like it's it's not
something that I would normally spend a
bunch of time on right and then and so
I'm like in the beginning I was like oh
okay cool you know and I look at it for
a second and when as soon as my brain
said ah this is not really sketchy I
would I would put it away right and I'd
be like okay you know I don't really
think that's that's worth anything right
but then as I as I had the experience
time and time again of those people
actually popping the thing that I didn't
think was sketchy
I'm starting to realize hey you know
Justin's Justin's sketchiness radar is
not completely you know locked in right
I I am not thinking everything is is
sketchy that is sketchy and I'm missing
things that that that are there right um
and so I think even if you don't think
it's a good finding if you respect the
hacker that you are are working with and
you you believe them to have a skill set
that you don't then it's very important
to take those those leads seriously and
really throw everything you've got at
them because um that difference in
exploitation experience or difference in
your your Spidey senses so to speak for
for that end point might be exactly the
combination that's needed to get that
bug to pop as long as you give it a
chance right does does that make sense
yeah absolutely yeah for sure I know I'm
I know I'm I I went I went into full
full Mentor mode there for a second but
I I think you're right I think that's I
think that's a valuable one as well yeah
absolutely is because as we said earlier
everyone has their own skill set
everyone I mean a lot of people
specialize in very Niche things as well
so if something comes to your plate it's
probably good to look at it and try and
peel it back and see what they're
seeing for
sure hey guys our sponsor project
Discovery has dropped a new tool in
collaboration with Google's own Mandan
team called TLD finder okay picture the
SubFinder but for top level domains did
I say anymore check it out
um so let's let's we've we've covered
the live hacking event stuff a little
bit we're we' done it backwards yeah so
Richard I'm so sorry because he's gonna
have to go in here and timestamp this
video and he's gonna be like mentorship
l mentorship l um but let's let's swing
back around
to what has made you go from essentially
zero successful experience in bug Bounty
at the beginning of this year to um what
are you in like 13th or something out of
like 100 at this last live hacking event
so a really remarkable performance um
and and a couple of the things we had on
here was
what how you choose targets and what you
choose to do with those targets so can
you talk a little bit about what your
experience has been with that and and um
how you how you pick the targets you go
for and how you approach them for sure
so when I'm looking at a Target it I try
and pick things which and I have a list
really if I need to like buy something
or if I need something new or a
subscription I will look to see if
there's a bug Bounty program for the
thing I'm trying to buy if there's a
competitor I can use which has a bug
Bounty program and I'll purposely buy it
from them so I can walk through the flow
in its entirety and buy something and
almost get like a two or maybe even a
freebie because it just makes so much
sense to do I'm going to buy it anyway
so I might as well try and get some like
additional EXP or exposure to it if I
can hack it so why not and that's been
pretty good um and has unlocked a lot of
attack surface for me and the other
thing as well is what services do you
currently use or can you start using
similar to the first point which gives
you one an edge on a Target or two has a
bug Bounty programing in itself so do
you already PVE something which is an
integration for a Target which you have
been looking at for example is quite
powerful and can unlock a lot of attack
surface and the reason why I start of
these two things is because it almost
like flows into your day-to-day life you
don't need to go out the way to buy
something else or learn something else
you're already familiar with it or you
need to do it anyway so it sort of makes
sense and there's less resistance there
and the other thing as well is in terms
of region and where you reside what can
you are you from the UK or you from the
US what services can you unlock or what
attack surface is unique and
geographically exclusive to you because
I guess we'll touch upon it shortly but
I've had a lot of success in unlocking a
lot of hard to unlock areas uh purely
because of the attack comp well the
unlock complexity to get there in the
first
place yeah I I I kind of mentioned this
a little bit um yesterday in the in the
talk that I gave for the critical think
but I have this theory on on bug Bounty
that a lot of that we should try to
maximize um what I call the attack
Vector value which is a function of the
impact of this specific attack Vector so
what what would you achieve if you were
able to pull off this attack um uh times
the uh probability of that attack attack
actually succeeding okay is there is
there like a is this a really a long
shot am I like you know dropping a
command in C prompt into like a you know
logging end point or something like that
FR um uh div divided by the friction um
to to actually try that attack Vector um
and so I I think that that friction
component is really is really the most
interesting variable in that equation um
because the the friction piece it it can
really it can really save you from dupes
it can say it can get you exclusive
scope it can get you access to things
that pentesters don't even get access to
because anybody who's been a pentester
consultant knows that when you roll up
to a pentest they're not handing you a
fully seeded account they're not handing
you a a you know a credit card you can
use to like buy the the stuff behind the
pay wall right you're pretty much having
the same thing that you have access to
as a bug Bounty Hunter so if if you
don't have access to it then the
pentester probably didn't as well so
there's there might be code living
Behind these these little um pay walls
or location Gates or whatever that uh
that nobody has ever assessed um and so
that that definitely that definitely
unlocks some some exclusive scope and I
think you found that at least what I've
observed is that sometimes you can go
really hard on on the parts of the scope
that are more accessible and then when
you move into those regionally locked
things or paywall locked things all of a
sudden everything just seems to work and
it just gets easier um which I think is
really encouraging as well right because
it's like you're not going up against
this really this really hardened things
anymore you've kind of found the hack to
getting access to the The Sweet
Spot and I think that's one piece of
advice I'll give to part-time Hunters as
well which I'm in hindsight I'm quite
happy it didn't bother me but if you AR
full-time hunting and you don't have
much time to hunt or as much as you
would like putting in an hour two hours
to go through that flow and go through
the very annoying process of signing up
to something or configuring your account
to support five different types of
flows putting that investment in will
probably pay off around 90% of the time
at some point and you will dig something
up you just have to put that investment
in initially which is what puts a lot of
people off from doing it in the first
place yeah it's hard I like your I like
your tip though of of actually
intentionally unlocking scope for
yourself with the products you you you
buy so it's not like I'm a hacker I'm
sitting here thinking okay what do I
hack and then I see a product and I'm
like all right I'll just pay the money
and buy that product and do the hacking
right that's great that's the that's the
you know we've got that little Christian
I'm gonna I'm gonna ask my video editor
to try to put this up on the screen
there's like the the Galaxy brain meme
right the small brain is like you know
public scope stuff the the the middle
brain is like you know oh I'm paying for
services right you know cuz I'm a hacker
and then the the Galaxy brain is like
really I'm going to you know go and and
use the services that I have and and and
or intentionally buy a service that has
a bug Bounty program for personal use um
and make that a part of my product
selection I don't know how he's going to
fit that into a little thing but yeah
sorry mate yeah sorry sorry Christian
but um but I I really like that idea and
I I I've actually heard I think it was
Ben naham say this one time where he was
like yeah I I use this credit card and I
was like yeah you know like just just
talking about credit card Point hacking
I was like oh this one really gives you
know more flexible points and is really
you know helpful and he's like yeah but
that one doesn't have a bug Bounty
program and I'm like damn that's true
man if you find like one bug right that
is way better than all these points that
I'm talking about right so intentionally
making a product selection for your
personal use surrounding whether uh
something has a bug bounding program or
not not only pays dividends from a
security perspective um but also can pay
actual dividends
literally for for for you to get
bounties that's that's great man
literally I really like that um let let
me ask you this so I guess you've had
experience as a pentester before going
into BG Bounty um but what what
vulnerability
classes have you have you found to be
most fruitful for you um going from
beginner to L and and then what
vulnerability classes have you recently
said wow this is something something
that I wasn't wasn't looking for quite
as much that I I really should have been
investing
in so originally I think a lot of
defaults and because of the amount of
them there are there's a lot of excess
broken access control so I focus on them
as my bread and butter and that was my
plan originally but as I started peeling
back and getting more familiar with
targets a lot of logicyoutube
xss there's so many everywhere that I
recommend everyone to at least have them
on your checklist somewhere to look but
that's primarily where I started off and
then I went to Vegas and I attended Ben
the harm sex talk and he done a talk on
ssrf and the talk was really good had
some workshops in there as well all good
stuff and not that the techniques were
anything new to me but I had the very
very harsh
realization of why aren't I looking for
ssrf the talk was on
ssrf and I sat there and I couldn't
answer it and I felt a bit silly because
I just thought there's no reason for me
not to look for this I have experienced
exploiting it in the past in a pentest
context I just never bothered looking
for
it so I took that away and I was all
right okay let's try and find some srf
and then for three weeks solid I think
it was I chain I escalated three SSRS
into RC with Alex Chapman for three
weeks one a week um which was incredible
and all headless browser exploitation
obviously that's Alex's Jam um but yeah
it just occurred to me like if you have
experience or some Competitive Edge
around whether it be a Target or V class
don't disregard that because that's
knowledge and experience you can very
easily put to use with the right mindset
when approaching a Target that was my
biggest takeway this extends to Industry
as well right like if you before you
were a hacker have experience in
whatever industry the the financing
industry the construction industry you
know the pharmaceutical industry right
there are almost certainly bug Bounty
programs out there that will utilize
those terms or the requirements of that
you know field the specific knowledge of
that field um which is is really really
helpful for you and gives you a
competitive Edge I that that's something
that that me you know as somebody who's
been forced to look at so many targets
because of live hacking events like I it
became a little bit less important to me
because I'm like well you know if if if
hacker one or bug crowd or whever is
going to just point me at these targets
I I got to be able to hack it but you
know when I'm in my off time when I'm
when I'm not hacking after these live
hacking events you know working on
targets where I have you know industry
specific knowledge uh could be fun so
I'm I'm gonna I'm gonna see man maybe uh
maybe there's some real estate um some
Real Estate websites that I can go hack
or something like that I can tell you
right now I have I can list some off
which are private but you most
definitely have access to them there's a
few I know there's a few huh huh I
hadn't I hadn't really I hadn't really
thought about that um so coming back to
what you said though you mentioned a
checklist and I know that you are very
structured and I don't know that we've
actually talked about this but I know
that you're very structured that you
take really good notes um do you
actually use a vul class checklist or
are you is your checklist mostly like
attack Vector ideation then that goes on
the checklist and then I'm checking
those off one by one yeah so when I
approach a Target where I've had
previous experience pen testing and have
like a base grounding on every not every
but most phone classes I use a threat
model approach on targets so I go on the
application sign up unlock everything I
possibly can every single flow go
through everything and then once I have
that context as a normal user I'll start
going through my burp history and
playing around with the app and when I
start peeling back the layers I try and
put down every single possible attack
Vector no matter how stupid it might
sound put down the attack Vector whether
that be because the functionality is
sketchy whether they're using a specific
technology whether the architecture
lends itself to that whatever it might
be and my whole aim when I'm going
through this process when I first
approach a Target is to come up with as
many attack vectors as humanly possible
so when I'm then hacking the target I
have a massive list of inspiration I can
actually look at and just get really
creative with and tick off one by one
and the idea is that it is a living
breathing list document which I can
never finish because the more familiar
you get with something the more ideas
you should have that's my premise of why
I do that and how I do it and for me
personally with the way I work and
needing notes just to do any basic
function of life in general um it's been
quite successful and you can pick back
up on the target you can look at this
list and go okay I didn't really try
that last time but it's on my list and
then you can start going down that route
and I feel like if you are in a
part-time capacity and your time is
quite sporadic and you can't just hit a
target for two three day solid that very
much lends itself towards that it's very
very useful yeah wow I I think this if I
had to to guess obviously there's a lot
of things going for you over the this
past 10 months that have worked out well
but if I had to guess I think this is
probably the number one thing that that
has served you well is your your
dedication to attack Vector ideation and
and it's actually it's starting to click
with me a little bit now because I've
heard you talk about this time and time
again and um I've even put it in some of
these presentations that I've been doing
um at Defcon and just yesterday for the
critical thinkers um the importance of
attack Vector ideation and how pivotal
that is I think it's probably the most
underrated skill in in bug Bounty um and
it seems like you have a good system for
that you you you you start preloading
this list you get this massive list
right and then you you know you start
working on the items and you allow those
you allow your your creativity to
trigger and you allow yourself to go
down different paths and then when you
get to a dead end a lot of people that
aren't creating this massive list
they're just getting stuck and they're
saying okay well I'm kind of you know
that didn't pan out I I I'm I'm I don't
know where to go next but but for you
you've got this document where you say
all right I don't know where to go next
back to the next item on the list and
then you you know you start from there
um
that's really that's really powerful
dude I I really I really respect that
approach is that something that you
think evolved from
more from more structured hacking like
you in the beginning you you wanted to
you know make sure you were you were
checking all the boxes with the own
classes and stuff like that or is that
just something is that a function of the
way that you live your life with the
note
taking so in the hacking context I think
that really started when I started doing
more code review type stuff because to
give everyone context I don't have a
developer background um at all I was
very traditional Blue Team Network
Administration sock and then pen testing
so that development background which a
lot of hackers have which is incredibly
useful to have I didn't have so when I
it all started when I tried to go for my
oswe
and I found it it it wasn't intuitive at
first when I was approaching these
codebases and some of the code bases
were Enterprise small Enterprise level
and I was just like well what have I
been doing for the last three hours like
where am I like I don't even I don't get
where I am like what's what's been going
on
and so true yeah and uh I that's when I
started coming up with the system and
when I tried to get into bug Bounty I
realized under the context I was doing
it and the constraint I was doing it
because in the mornings I'd say do stuff
for critical thinking and then I do my
main job and then in the evenings I'll
do bug hunting or it might be completely
different and in the mornings I'll be
bug hunting and whatever I realize that
that context switching is incredibly
taxing mentally it is incredibly taxing
and it's exhausting as well and the idea
of notes and applying that methodology
when I'm approaching a target
takes a bit of that mental tax away
because you can see your notes you can
almost it helps you prime yourself to
get back into that right okay this is
what I'm going for next dude I I'm so
glad I have you as a writer like like
this this is the perfect guy for the
writer the guy that like lives and
breathes notes um that's that's awesome
dude that that that is really great um
yeah I think I think that is definitely
one of the the major components that
that contributed to your success for
sure um true man all right man I think
that is the end of what we've what we've
got on this list here um do you have any
oh oh no I almost forgot the bugs we got
we got to go we got to go to the bugs um
all right dude you you actually popped
some some three pretty solid ones on
here um so so let's let's start with
this first one atto on on fintech Bank
tell tell us how you pulled that off
yeah so this one was one of my first
bugs ever paid bugs in bug Bounty um it
was my first one on hacker one and
um the it was the first one was a crit
and after that I was very much like I
set the bar high high for myself but
then I also knew I wanted to like keep
that energy and keep going which didn't
pay me dividends the second time I
didn't get a crit but it was still good
to get a crit first time anyway um so
this one was good it involved a lot of
unlocking attack surface um and I was
trying to basically peel back this
Target and understand what would hurt
them and where some areas are which
probably haven't been looked at as much
and in order to unlock this attack
surface and really getting to the bottom
of it I ended up creating
seven men might have been eight actually
real bank accounts under my name and
with different payment providers which
has hurt me bit in the past 10 months um
it has hurt me quite a lot I'm not going
to lie and there's at one point I was
even getting messages from like bank
fraud teams like who are you why are you
sending one penny with this nonsensical
string who is Justin gner why has he
sent you an international pay
go and um yeah it was it was an
interesting experience but that for me
of unlocking the attack surface and
going through all that pain did pay off
quite well and this all started with
really this started before the bug
hunting but there's a lot of newer UK
Banks which when you get a payment you
can like respond back to someone with an
emoji or a message and I was thinking
okay call functionality maybe a little
bit excessive I don't know why that's
necessary but how's that actually
working and some of these banks have a
web app portion so how is that rendered
and what are they letting through
because emojis and like that's that just
had that little spidey sense
tingling and throughout me approaching
this Target and Performing This research
um I started the reason why I set up
with so many different payment providers
not just bank accounts um I wanted to
understand what different providers
allowed what different character sets
and how much flexibility they allowed to
be sent with say a payment or a request
or whatever it might be and that's where
the magic happened so primarily for EU
now but a lot of EU based fintech
related companies did something called
the um open banking API and this is a
open API spec that anyone can look at
online and you can check which banks are
compliant with which areas of the API
and it's basically an API spec which is
defined for if a bank a wants to send
money to bank B and you're both in the
EU or you're both UK based this is what
the API looks like Al so this is like a
like a B2B like a businesso business uh
or a bank to oh bank to bank b2v uh API
that's that's pretty cool and it's it's
standardized across all these different
banks yeah so my understanding is it's
primarily for EU based Banks because
there's a lot of um there's a lot of
like functionality and overflows now
where when you say send a payment you
can log into your account and there's
like this overflow and all the banks
like know each other they're
pre-selected so you can just click your
bank and then it takes you to the proper
login page and does a lot of the leg
work for you but the interesting part
about this is there's a lot of
functionality there for one and two in
the open banking spec it tells you like
what data types to expect and how long
the fields are and things like that um
and compared to the open banking spec
and what was implemented I found there's
a lot of discrepancies in terms of what
was allowed and um what wasn't the one
thing that was standardized across all
of them however was a very strong and
limited um reference in a
payment and that was hard set across all
um EU UK
providers however when I was looking at
what I can send and what I can't send
this is where I roped you in and why I
did get fraud ringing their alarm bells
and every everyone like that um I wanted
to look at how International payments
are handle right because open banking is
more like EU toe what what happens with
International and equally with
International banking each bank has to
support their local character set right
so like that could be anything anything
could end up in there really um and that
is where I managed to figure out that
one of these inputs was vulnerable um
and I essentially used it to achieve
account takeover through means of storex
sucess by sending a payment of like a
penny
to greet me yeah and when they open the
payment they go who is this guy why is
he sending me a Penny open it and bang
account take over wow dude that's that's
really solid I'm going to be like a
proud dad for a second here and just
highlight all of these amazing things
that led to this this bug okay um first
thing that that just bum you know just
stood out to me so clearly
was how far you went on this target
right and and I think we talked about
that right we were like hey you should
really spend a lot of time on this
target um and you opened up seven
different bank accounts in order to to
get access to all this different scope
right when we talk about scope expansion
we're not just talking about okay s my
card pay five bucks you know now I got
access to the premium product woohoo
sort of thing you went and you filled
out forms and you you know dealt with
fraud emails and you damaged I don't
know what the UK equivalent of your
credit score is but like you know like
it's on the floor it's on the floor open
a bunch of stuff um in order to achieve
this which is very dedicated um and and
then you're also the Emoji piece was
really was really interesting the Emoji
piece in these different character sets
because the way that you're you're
looking at this situation you have a um
you know a spidey sense for for what
type of data needs to be we and and what
kind of um character sets need to be
supported um so I thought that was
really I thought that was really a great
example of actually thinking about and
processing how data flows through
applications right and that's that's
definitely a core skill that a lot of
hackers need to understand is where that
data is flowing and what type of data
we're dealing with and then diving deep
into that open open banking API and
seeing okay well for for EU to EU
there's this but then what happens
internationally and thinking about those
edge cases in that scenario it's just
all of it comes together and culminates
in an amazing bug with great impact too
I mean if you can send somebody money
and then you you take over their bank
that is that is bad um yeah so I just I
love all the different components of
that that came together um and and how
they they they bounced off of each other
so you know I said I I gave a disclaimer
I I'm I'm proud I'm happy with that let
me just give you a little round Applause
little round Applause there um it was um
yeah it was good and I feel like fintech
targets I've almost lent into naturally
um from prior testing experience and
also after approaching this Target and
the amount of attack surface that was
there I started to realize and then when
I discovered the open Bank in apis Spec
and all these discrepancies and things
like that it sort of was just it just
made sense for me that okay there's a
lot of weird things happening here which
probably weren't ever designed for an
emoji to end up in like as a thank you
back to payment and things like that
yeah and yeah it was uh when you start
seeing them sort of things it can be
interesting to peel them back and figure
out why they're implemented and how
they're implemented yeah 100% man well
done well done so we I I've obviously I
knew I knew that story because I played
a little bit of a part in it but um I'm
not sure that I've actually heard these
other two so hit me hit me with this uh
zero interaction
atto yeah so on one of the Targets in
the hackell
cup I found an inherent design floor by
complete accident at the time but now
it's being very much integrated into my
methodology and something to think about
on other targets um but it this concept
of understanding which endpoints expose
properties of an object that you're
looking at and you're
attacking um and what I mean by this
is without trying to abstract it too
much if you have like a user object for
example that you're attacking in one way
or another can't take over
excess noting down which endpoints
throughout the application ecosystem or
or entire ecosystem as a whole which
different endpoints expose which
different properties of this same object
and documenting them is very very
powerful because objects can have
different types right so when you look
at a user object for example you can
have active inactive deleted invited
revoked banned just one example there's
so many different states and objects can
live in depending on its context and
being able to identify these end points
which expose these properties of the
object and hitting these same end points
but iterating the object through a
different context every
time found some really really creative
bugs for me because there's endpoints
for example which were accessible to all
users which is completely normal
behavior they should be accessible
that's a way it's designed but when an
object is in a very specific State
hitting that same endpoint would expose
like an invitation token for example
which again all users can see this uh
Endo but on this specific property on
this specific object if you hit it when
it's in the right State you might
disclose something quite juicy in this
context and invitation token and I found
once I realized this on uh Target in
particular I realized that this was
pretty much everywhere and the impact of
that was a lot of zero interaction atto
because you could just take over other
users accounts if they were say invited
or whatever state they're in because
there are specific endpoints not all but
specific endpoints which would expose
these additional properties of that
object and let anyone read them if that
makes sense yeah no that that makes
total sense and I think you also see
this often in in the graphql world as
well like like that is one of the the I
don't know if this app was graphql or
not but you know you understanding what
data types are on what what specific or
what uh data types have what properties
and using different um queries and
mutations and such to be able to um grab
those properties out of these specific
objects that might be at different
states um definitely definitely a
powerful thing and it it can affect um
traditional apis as well like rest apis
um and and sometimes you'll even see I
don't know if you seen this one before
but uh some of these traditional apis
will have sort of like graphql esque
functionality where you can add a query
parameter that says like include or
something like that and then name like a
sub object or a subproperty and that
will also be included in the API
response only if you put that in the
query parameter right exactly so so
those sort of things I I think can
really and and I like the way that you
mi mixed that with state state changes
as well invited blocked removed you know
whatever um as the that data type as
that user type evolves um you'll see
different things in those different
states yeah absolutely and I feel like
that's something why I think it was AR
Angel said that he finds a lot of like
delete based broken access control and
idols and the reason for that is when
someone's testing this and say you might
have a typical flow of like using aoriz
and just repeating request whatever in
them operations that's a onetime
operation once that's complete you can't
run it again so therefore it's not going
to show up as runable but if you like
just drop that request entirely then
resend it when you're doing your testing
that's why a lot of these like weird
delete based and maybe more context
based things with these properties exist
because that's a hole in a lot of
hunters um scope I think I've noticed
anyway yeah absolutely that that is
that's really interesting man I I I
hadn't really figured out the reason why
that was the case where that a lot of
delete idors made it through but that
makes that makes a lot of sense in those
those Frameworks that will automatically
do the access control testing for you
and it and it reminds me of a bug that I
found um within the past couple months
uh where there was an entity that that
you could modify explicitly right um and
so you know the request just had that
object's ID in it right and one of those
properties of that object was the
organization that the object belonged to
right um and you if you tried to modify
somebody else's object with their their
entity their organization ID in there
right um then it would fail and say
you're not allowed to do that but if you
put your organization ID in the body and
you referenced somebody else's object
right then and Not only would it allow
you to modify it but it would steal it
over to your organization so so now so
now the object is gone from their
organization it's in your organization
which is effect to Integrity right or
and in some case availability depending
on the the services that that might
break their whole setup um but it also
affects confidentiality right because if
you didn't modify all the properties of
that object you just modified a couple
of them the the remaining properties are
still at values that they were when they
were in this this victims organization
so you can leak data about that object
as well um so it really hits the CIA
Triad really nicely and takes them all
off yeah exactly so it get turns into a
really really impactful vulnerability um
so very good man all right let's let's
jump to this next one it's an ssrf and
and we know we know big things come from
ssrf for you lately so yeah so as I
touched upon earlier I like to on the
targets that lend themselves to it and
I've looked at a couple now or I like to
look at the ecosystem as a whole rather
than individual components or
applications of it and there's
some ecosystems and targets which will
offer something like a developer based
um service where you can test your own
stuff and integrate into them but in
like a test context and the test
environment completely
um and equally more specifically I found
that on one of these ecosystems they
actually allow you to tie and piggyback
off the back of the ool configuration so
you can use them to perform all of your
like authentication and then you doal
with the rest sort of thing
and when I was looking at this um
ecosystem in particular I realized that
there's a lot of assumptions made in
other controls on hosts and EMP points
that if something comes from this host
or something comes from this endpoint it
is safe it is to be trusted it is okay
um without realizing in other parts of
the
ecosystem there's ways that user input
and developers can sign up and also host
something on these same endpoints and
also piggyback off of this same config
which you
offer and it was quite interesting
because I was originally looking for SSR
s in one area of the Target and I
couldn't quite get it because it was
complaining about the host that was in
use and I thought okay fair enough put
it in my notes come back to that later
again the notes come in use or um
carried I'm looking at the um iwolf
configuration and it turns out there's
an area where you could add your own
redirect URI value to redirect to your
own application at some point in their
ecosystem and at some point in the flow
so I was thinking okay what host has
this reside on and it started to match
up quite nicely and I thought okay so
now I can satisfy some of these
validations that they put in place of
the host based part right when I was
looking for srf that it needs to reside
on this host um you can't look at any
other host apart from this host that has
designed business functionality that's
all you can
do and when I started playing around
with aolf um if you play around with the
code parameter and if you put in like a
compl compl
nonsensical um value in this Cod
parameter like blah blah blah critical
thing whatever it might be critical
critical
critical I did do that for my PC um you
can actually abuse that to go straight
to the redirect URI value and it just
redirects you providing that the
redirect URI value has actually been
whitelisted on the back
end the the are we talking about the
response type or the the is is that what
you're talking about sorry yes the the
response mode or response type one of
those two yeah nice whatever one it is
you can put in a completely made up
value and providing that the redirect
URI value has been Whit listed on the
back end it will just straight redirect
you to that value so I thought okay
that's interesting and at this time the
the puzzle pieces weren't really falling
in place I was just pondering and
thinking that is interesting and then we
got on a call and I was like
there it is and I tried it and it worked
so essentially what you could do is in
this ecosystem you could sign up as a
developer host your own or have some
control over their oil flow on a host
which they used heavily for their own um
input validation and essentially abuse
that whole flow to put a nonsense call
um value in and hit the redirect URI
every time and using that approach
I managed to get quite a lot of SSRS and
it was like an inherent design flaw
because I don't think when the two teams
didn't really talk when that
architectural decision decision was made
um and that was when I realized that
spending time on a wider ecosystem and
understanding all the components of one
can be incredibly useful because
otherwise that would have been a dead
end yeah popped it including the dev
stuff right this is this is one of the
areas that I think is the most fruitful
for bug Bounty stuff is going and
registering with this specific platform
as a integration partner or like use
their SDK or like you know there there's
there's tons of of mostly untouched
stuff there because people don't want to
go you know down the rabbit hole of like
all right now I got to go like set up
this website that like emulates this
integration and set up this JS file and
blah D blah D blah and um that used to
be something that I would do you know
just as like okay I'm going to do this
because I'm going to get deeper and like
attack this specific portion of the
scope but now dude it's so much easier
with AI you can just feed it you can
just feed it the page and be like hey
generate the um you know the client side
request to trigger this flow and it'll
do it and I'm like oh my gosh this is
amazing um but I think that that's I
think that's a really good takeaway for
for the listeners of of
like looking at that the ecosystem as a
whole like you're talking about looking
at the dev related stuff and then I I
really like this trick that that you
mentioned of of you weaponizing the oath
flow to to create an open redirect
because if you like you said I think
it's I think it's the response type
because that it would be response type
code right exactly so so if you put some
nonsensical value in the response type
it will often just redirect back to the
redirect URL because that's the way to
inform the the host that was initiating
the oath flow that something failed
right so boom you you got an open
redirect and and that's got to be widely
applicable in so many environments right
yeah absolutely I feel like especially
now all these Integrations that exist
and when you start looking at more
ecosystem based targets and this is
heavily used in fintech as well there's
a lot of test environments test flows
test accounts test data all this sort of
thing all these sort of things which you
can actually abuse to satisfy the
requirements that some of their other
defenses rely on in some cases because
the hosts might be the same and maybe
even the end points match up if they're
checking that so it can be incredibly
fruitful to go through and understand
okay on this is what I can set up this
is where my inputs my inputs are and
matching that up with production and the
rest of their scope yeah dude as I'm
thinking about this I'm thinking I'm
thinking I need to go try some stuff
right now actually because I'm I think
there might be a way for me to exploit a
bug that I've been wanting to exploit
for a very long time so I think we're g
to call that a pod man I think we're g
to call that a pod you got got anything
else you want to say at the end or or am
I free to go that's all good that's all
good that's all good go and have fun did
you see my eyes just expanded there for
a second I'm like I got to go I got to
go all right that's the Pod peace
everybody peace
and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb doow
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack along alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there
[Music]